Jamie Parkinson



Recent theoretical physics graduate and full-stack developer with an emphasis on the frontend, passionate about developing exceptional web applications with excellent UI/UX and about original and intelligent data visualisation. Have worked in a wide variety of research fields, from atomic physics to quantum foundations and nucleation theory. Care deeply about clear communication both in and out of science, and about the importance of work with social value.

education

UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON (UCL) - MSci Theoretical Physics (First Class Honours)

2012-2016

- Recipient of prizes for the **top performance in my 1st year** and for the **best MSci research project**. Average mark of **well over 80%** each year, with around **90%** in all computational modules (**Java** and **Mathematica**).

BILBOROUGH COLLEGE, NOTTINGHAM - A-Levels: A*A*A* in Maths, Further Maths and Physics

2010-2012

THE NOTTINGHAM BLUECOAT SCHOOL - GCSEs: 9 A*s, 4 As

2005-2010

experience

DRFOCUSED - Product Developer and Data Scientist

09/2016 - present

- Working on the product frontend - including rebuilding the whole web app in React. Also investigating potential insights from user data.

PiC - PERFORMANCE IN CONTEXT - Product Development Intern

07/2016 - 09/2016

- Working across PiC's stack (**Flask**, **PostgreSQL** and various **JavaScript** frameworks). Given a **lead role** developing a new product: took a **React** web app from idea to minimum viable product in 1 week.

UCL/UNIVERSITY OF HELSINKI - Summer Research

06-09/2015

- Awarded an EPSRC research grant to conduct research into the thermodynamics of clusters of sulphuric acid and water, with potential applications in **climate science**. Successful work (using lots of **Python**, **bash** and some **FORTRAN**) led to being funded to travel to Finland in September to present, discuss and build upon our results at the University of Helsinki.
- Published as first author in Molecular Simulation.

UCL RYDBERG GROUP - Summer Research

06-09/2014

- Awarded an EPSRC research grant to research the the acceleration of antihydrogen atoms for the AEgIS research group at CERN. Developed software in C++, researched a variety of high-performance techniques and developed a novel new method of caching values on a 3D grid.

other projects

INTERACTIVE LECTURE NOTES FOR QUANTUM COMPUTATION - jamieparkinson.github.io

05/2016 - present

- A personal project, developing interactive lecture notes for topics in quantum computation using HTML & CSS and D3.

SMARTPHONE APPS FOR MEDICINE

01-03/2015

- Worked in a group developing apps to be used by patients in medical contexts. Took a lead role in software development, using the **lonic** framework (including **AngularJS**) to develop cross-platform apps. Was commended by my supervisors and peers for the quality of work and my teamwork in this project.

MORE THINGS THAN I CAN REMEMBER!

~2004 - present

- My first website had a yellow background, a lot of HTML marquees, and some awful effects copied off of *dynamicdrive.com*. Since then I've developed Wordpress plugins in PHP, scientific code in MATLAB, Mathematica, IDL and R, tried my hand at Ruby, F# and PerI, coded countless pointless scripts in Python and bash, and just about got my head around LTFX.

interests

I'm an experienced orchestral double bass player, having lead and co-lead bass sections in a variety of high quality orchestras. I find orchestral playing to be an extremely fulfilling experience, involving huge amounts of focus and the ability to respond intuitively and instantaneously to what others are doing.

References are available upon request.